<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Entropy maximizer</title><link href="http://rcalsaverini.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://rcalsaverini.github.io/feeds/bayesian-modelling.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://rcalsaverini.github.io/</id><updated>2010-08-03T23:55:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Bayesian Hierarchical Models</title><link href="http://rcalsaverini.github.io/bayesian-hierarchical-models.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-03T23:55:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Rafael S. Calsaverini</name></author><id>tag:rcalsaverini.github.io,2010-08-03:bayesian-hierarchical-models.html</id><summary type="html">
&lt;hr  class="madoko" data-line="1"&gt;

&lt;p data-line="3"&gt;&lt;span data-line="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Bayesian hierarchical modeling is a statistical model written in multiple levels (hierarchical form) that estimates the parameters of the posterior distribution using the Bayesian method.&lt;span data-line="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;[1]&lt;span data-line="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; The sub-models combine to form the hierarchical model, and the Bayes’ theorem is used to integrate them with the observed data, and account for all the uncertainty that is present. The result of this integration is the posterior distribution, also known as the updated probability estimate, as additional evidence on the prior distribution is acquired.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent" data-line="5"&gt;&lt;span data-line="5"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Frequentist statistics, the more popular foundation of statistics, has been known to contradict Bayesian statistics due to its treatment of the parameters as a random variable, and its use of subjective information in establishing assumptions on these parameters. However, Bayesians argue that relevant information regarding decision making and updating beliefs cannot be ignored and that hierarchical modeling has the potential to overrule classical methods in applications where respondents give multiple observational data. Moreover, the model has proven to be robust, with the posterior distribution less sensitive to the more flexible hierarchical priors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="indent" data-line="7"&gt;&lt;span data-line="7"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Hierarchical modeling is used when information is available on several different levels of observational units. The hierarchical form of analysis and organization helps in the understanding of multiparameter problems and also plays an important role in developing computational strategies.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span data-line=""&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</summary><category term="Bayesian modelling"></category><category term="Hierarchical models"></category></entry></feed>